Guide to the Harold Caparn collection, [ca. 1880s-1990s]
Caparn, Harold collection
- Series III. Other Caparn Family Members
  - Oliver Chamberlain Jr.
    - Postcards - Collection of Oliver Chamberlain, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Aerial View. Regarding writings of H.A. Great Naval Arch erected in honor of Admiral Geo. Dewey, Hero of Manila, New York. Parade through Dewey Arch.
    - "Gardens by Design Informal garden design by Harold Caparn Consulting Landscape Architect Brooklyn Botanical Garden 1912-1945", undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Photocopy. Oliver Chamberlain. Landscapes and writings of Harold Caparn.
    - Articles by Oliver Chamberlain (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Photographs of landscape architecture done by Harold Caparn used by Oliver Chamberlain for his book, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Includes Briarcliff Mansion.
    - Copies of Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Copies of Photographs - used by Oliver Chamberlain for his book, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Report - "A History of Mountain Home" (copy), December 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Thesis by Susan Kay Hartman. East Tennessee State University
  - Oliver Chamberlain Sr.
    - Chamberlain Florist, 1924-1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      3 Photographs of Chamberlain Florists and photocopies, Short Hills, NJ. Catalog of "Annuals and Perennials", Chamberlain, Florist. Parsonage Hill Road, Short Hills, NJ. (1931); Photocopy of Mitchell Medal awarded to Oliver Chamberlain (1935) by Hentry F. Mitchell Co. Philadelphia, PA. (1924-1935)
    - Chamberlain Florist, 1924-1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Photographs include Chamberlain Florist delivery truck, Oliver Chamberlain at door to shop, Chamberlain Florist exterior, Chamberlain Florist interior, Chamberlain Florist (greenhouse), Oliver Chamberlain's home, Oliver Chamberlain property (landscape), Employee with truck (Chamberlain in the background), Nursery,
    - Oliver Chamberlain, 1935-1940 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Photographs include Estate Gardener, Oliver Chamberlain with Janet(1939); Kathleen, Oliver Chamberlain and Oliver Jr.; Gardener's Cottage; Portion of Gardener's Cottage; Oliver Chamberlain in Greenhouse; Lake next to Reade Estate; Oliver Chamberlain and dog; (Reade Estate in Deal, NJ)... Small white envelope contains more photographs from Reade Estate in Deal, NJ)
    - Rosenwald Estate, c. 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Art Installation by W. Lutz. Short Essay by Oliver Chamberlain regarding photograph.
    - Rosenwald Estate, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      "Summerhome", Tennis Courts and side view of Alverthorpe
    - Rosenwald Estate, c. 1940, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Photographs include Oliver Chamberlain with estate pickup truck; 3 unidentified estate gardeners for estate; 4 garden crew, Oliver Chamberlain with Oliver Jr and sister Janet in front of truck. (c. 1940)
    - Rosenwald Estate, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Photographs include "gardener's house", connected shed, potting shed, greenhouse, view of greenhouse and Oliver Chamberlain in greenhouse.
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Bartlet, Margaret Farrington. Down the Mountain: A Book about the Ever-Changing Soil, 1963 Illustrations by Rhys Caparn
Hale, Robert B. Rhys Caparn (signed by Rhys Caparn)